Breed-Mumford papers
Connecticut Historical Society
Breed-Mumford Papers
1752-1829
Connecticut Historical Society, Hartford, Connecticut
Breed-Mumford family
1.5 linear feet (3 boxes)
Scope and Content
The collection was initially processed by Ruth Blair and re-processed in 2005 to provide improved storage conditions. The records remain in the order originally processed.
The Breed family papers include the records of Gershom and his sons John McLaren, Simeon and Jesse, and of the partnership of Simeon and Jesse. Of interest are lottery tickets sold to raise funds for the Norwich Channel and a hand drawn map of the road between Preston and Voluntown, 1829.
The Mumford family papers consist almost entirely of records from the Revolutionary War. The muster rolls and pay rolls are arranged alphabetically by the name of the captain, or other ranking officer if no captain is listed. The enlistments and bounties are organized chronologically by year, but not by month. The military orders have been arranged alphabetically by the name of the highest-ranking officer mentioned in the document.
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the collection.
Accruals
The collection is closed.
Subject Headings
Personal Names
Breed, Gershom; Breed, John McLaren.; Breed, Simeon, b. 1763.; Breed, Jesse.
Family Names
Mumford family.
Geographic Names
United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783
Genre Forms
Account books -- 1762-1784; Account books -- Connecticut -- Norwich -- 1762-1784; Muster rolls.; Payrolls.; Orders (military records).
Contents:
- I. Breed family papers, 1754-1829
  - Gershom Breed account book, 1762-1784 (Volume 1)
  - Correspondence, legal papers, insurance documents, 1769-1816 (Box 1, Folder 1-15)
  - Map of Preston-Voluntown Road, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Assorted unidentified documents (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bills, receipts, notes, etc., 1754-1826, undated (Box 1, Folder 18-32)
  - Norwich Channel Lottery tickets, undated (Box 1, Folder 33-35)
  - Norwich Channel Lottery tickets, undated (Box 2, Folder 1-17)
- II. Mumford family papers, 1752-1794
  - Correspondence, legal documents, financial records, 1752-1794, undated (Box 2, Folder 18-32)
  - Military journal, 1776, 1777 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Muster rolls and pay rolls, 1775-1783 (Box 3, Folder 2-13)
  - Commissary records, wage receipts, privateering documents, returns (Box 3, Folder 14-20)
  - Enlistments and bounties, ca. 1775-1783 (Box 3, Folder 21-24)
  - Military orders, ca. 1775-1783 (Box 3, Folder 25-26)